Listen to a short talk on biology.
Today, we are going to continue our discussion of social insects, focusing on the
Argentine ant,
which as you might guess is a species of ant that are natives to Argentina.
We’ll consider what happened to this type of ant after some members of the
species move to California from their original habitat.
Ok, well, in Argentina, these Argentine ants behave like most ant species around the world.
They fight other ants of the same species if those ants are from some
other nests.
But the Argentine ants living in California behave differently.
Ants from different nests form a single large colony.
Within this colony, there is little aggression among ants from different nests.
And when they fight insects from outside their colony, the Argentine ants can quickly
recruit a huge army from their network of nests.
This of course gives them advantages over other ants’ species.
So then, why do Argentine ants behave differently in California than they do in Argentina?
Well, using genetic testing, researches found that all the Argentine ants in California were very similar genetically.
You see,
when the first Argentine ants came to California, their population must have been very small，
and all the later generations of Argentine ants there must be descended from the
same few ancestors.
So they are all closely related.
This discovery is important,
because for most social insects, membership in a colony is based on how closely
related they are genetically.